Neo Owens

Forked River, NJ 08731♦ (201) 888-0157 ♦ owens.nehemiah@gmail.com ♦ LinkedIn Profile: linkedin.com/in/nehemiahowens

RESUME OBJECTIVE

Experienced developer with 5+ years experience. Specializing in .NET web and console application development using ASP.NET, C#, and SQL Server. Searching for an opportunity to learn and apply new and emerging technologies. Experience as a developer has enhanced my ability to design, develop, test, and deploy console and web applications.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

PARTNER ENGINEERING AND SCIENCE

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER | SEPT 2017 - CURRENT

- Design, develop, and test .NET applications using C# in Visual Studio, SQL Server Database, JavaScript, and HTML.
- Modify and enhance existing .NET applications and SQL Server processes for efficiency and better performance.
- Develop ad-hoc queries, views, functions, stored procedures and sql jobs to process data efficiently.
- Integrate data between external HR and project management systems using .NET applications and SQL Server.
- Integrate data into .NET web applications as well as exportable documents through SQL Server Reporting Services reports.
- Develop and maintain Power BI reports for Operations Managers, Principles, and Executives by importing data from multiple sources, creating the data model, and creating pages with interactive visuals.

UNITEDHEALTH GROUP

APPLICATION DEVELOPER | OCT 2015 - MARCH 2017

- Designed and maintained client side screens as well as claim processing applications.
- Collaborated with a team of analysts, developers, subject matter experts, and leaders for functional specifications and solutions.
- Developed unit test plans and manipulated data to test requirements and quality of product.
- Retrieved, stored, and manipulated data in a claims database.
- Analyzed EDI 837 Institutional and Professional Health Care Claims.
- Supported triage and resolution of defects to refine and improve quality using Application Life Cycle software.

SYSTEMS ANALYST | MAY 2014 - OCT 2015

- Obtained, interpreted, and analyzed business requirements and issues.
- Prepared and executed test cases to ensure the quality of claims processing applications.
- Acted as the liaison between Business and Systems Analysts, Developers, and project management groups.
- Performed documentation and communication activities for technical and business personnel.
- Collaborated with a team of analysts, developers, subject matter experts, and leaders for solution assessment.
- Developed Unit Test Plans to test coding changes and manipulate data to ensure desired results using debugger.
- Supported triage and resolution of defects to refine and improve quality using Application Life Cycle software.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Science in Information Technology

Montclair State University/2012

KEY SKILLS

- Programming: C#, ASP.UNet, .Net Core, Javascript, JQuery, React, Node.js
- Software: Visual Studio, SQL Server Management Studio, Power BI, Visual Code
- Repositories: Github, Azure DevOps
- DBMS:SQL Server, LINQ